Guide to the Cornell University College of Veterinary Medicine Flower-Sprecher Veterinary Library records, 1897-2004
Cornell University College of Veterinary Medicine Flower-Sprecher Veterinary Library records, 1897-2004
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Cornell University College of Veterinary Medicine Flower-Sprecher Veterinary Library records, 1897-2004
24-15-3366
Cornell University. College of Veterinary Medicine. Flower-Sprecher Veterinary Library
3.4 cubic ft.
Subject files, accession records, and photographs.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Subject files, accession records, and photographs created by the Flower-Sprecher Veterinary Library at the Cornell University College of Veterinary Medicine.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
The library at the Cornell University College of Veterinary Medicine was founded on September 21, 1897. It was originally named after New York State governor, Roswell P. Flower, but became the Flower-Sprecher Veterinary Library in 1992 when it was renamed to recognize the generosity of Dr. and Mrs. Isidor I. Sprecher.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Subject files, accession records, and photographs created by the Flower-Sprecher Veterinary Library at the Cornell University College of Veterinary Medicine.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell University. College of Veterinary Medicine. Flower-Sprecher Veterinary Library.
Subjects:
Veterinary medicine -- Study and teaching.; Veterinary libraries.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIAL
See also the John B. Taylor and Simon Henry Gage correspondence, #24-4-m.1021, for more information about early funding for the library
SERIES LIST
Series I. Subject Files
Box: 1 and 2
Series II. Photographs
Box: 1
Series III. Accession Records, Requisitions
Boxes: 1-3
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Subject Files
  - Founding, 1897, 1901 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Histories of the Library, 1930-2004, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Administration - General, 1925, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Alpha Correspondence, B-C, ca. 1930-1947 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Alpha Correspondence, G-O, ca. 1930-1947 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Alpha Correspondence, R-W, ca. 1930-1947 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Alumni Room Project, 1940-1945 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Archives
    - College Archives, 2002-2004 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - College Historian/Ann Traitor, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Organization Plans, ca. 1970s (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Photo Classification, ca. 1970s (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - College newsletters (incomplete run) and miscellany, 1962-1981 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Catalog Cards, ca. 1970s (Box 3)
  - Buildings and Facilities
    - General, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Equipment - H.J. Bool Co., 1924-1932 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Equipment - Library Bureau, 1924-1938 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Pictures on Walls, 1931, 1937, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Move to Schurman - Memoranda, 1954-1957 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Move to Schurman - Equipment, 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Move to Schurman - Space Allotment, 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Move to Schurman - Moving Plans, 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Move to Schurman - Clocks, Switches, Phones, Dumbwaiter, Keys, 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Move to Schurman - Revisions, 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Move to Schurman - Miscellaneous, 1954-1957 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Floor Plans and Equipment Inventories, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Card Catalog Filing Rules, ca. 1960s (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Exhibits
    - Women of the Vet School, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Horse Portraiture, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - James Law, ca. 1970s (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Miscellaneous, ca. 1970s (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Faculty Portraits in the Library, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Faculty Publications - catalog cards
    - Henry Asmus (Box 3)
    - Earl Louis Brunett (Box 3)
    - Samuel H. Burnett (Box 3)
    - Pierre A. Fish (Box 3)
    - James N. Frost (Box 3)
    - Simon Henry Gage (Box 3)
    - Charles Hayden (Box 3)
    - Grant Sherman Hopkins (Box 3)
    - James Law (Box 3)
    - Veranus A. Moore (Box 3)
  - Gifts
    - Alumni Gifts to the Library, ca. 1960-1970 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Gift Books, ca. 1929-1958 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Gift Books - James Law, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Gift Books - Veranus Moore, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Handouts
    - General, ca. 1950-1969 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - General - legal sized, ca. 1950-1969 (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - Reference Sources, ca. 1950-1969 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Reference, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - General - legal sized, ca. 1950-1969 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Library Humor, ca. 1960s (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Newsletter, 1974-1982 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Rare Books - List, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Required Book Lists, 1935-1962 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Serials
    - Lists, 1898-1923, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Lists, ca. 1935, 1957, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Lists, 1962, 1967, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Subjects to be Indexed, ca. 1960-1975 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Staff
    - Burnett, Nellie, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Heyns, Erla, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Williams, E. Clifford, 1961-1996 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Williams, E. Clifford: certificate of appreciation (oversize), 1946 (Folder Mss Box 41)
    - Whitaker, Susanne, ca. 1977 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Baker Institute, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - CVM history, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Don't Forget the Horse Doctor, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Exhibition: "In Her Footsteps: Early Women Graduates in the College of Veterinary Medicine, 1910-1940", 2003 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Vet education - NYU Endowment Fund, 19-- (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Women Veterinarians, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Book Lists from Old Library, 1898-1946 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Annual Reports, 1926-1961 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Administrative Data, 1946-1951 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Library Plans, 1947-1953 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Roswell Pettibone Flower, 1993-2003 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Library Society Kick-Off-Binder, March 9. 2001 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Series II. Photographs
  - Entry in Veterinary Education Center, ca. 2002 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Reunion Display, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - "Photos Used in 'A Walk thru Flower Library'", ca. 1970s (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - University Photo Publicity Shots, ca. 2000 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Susanne Whitaker's 25th Anniversary, June 2002 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Library Society, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Happy 100th Birthday Mrs. Sprecker - Photo Book, 2013 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Veterinary Library Photos, various dates (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Veterinary Library Slides, 1898-1946 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Veterinary Library Society, 1990s (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Veterinary Library Centennial-contact sheets, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Series III. Accession Records, Requisitions
  - "Flower Fund", 1975-1983 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - "Bindery Record", 1927-1948 (Box 2)
  - untitled bound volume (large), ca. 1897-1899 (Box 3)
  - untitled bound volume (large), 1899-1907 (Box 3)
  - untitled bound volume (large), 1907-1917 (Box 3)
  - untitled bound volume (large), 1917-1928 (Box 3)
  - untitled bound volume, 1928-1931 (Box 3)
  - untitled bound volume, 1931-1936 (Box 3)
  - untitled bound volume, 1936-1942 (Box 3)
  - untitled bound volume, 1942-1947 (Box 3)
  - untitled bound volume, 1940-1946 (Box 2)
  - untitled bound volume, 1947-1951 (Box 2)
  - untitled bound volume, 1951-1963 (Box 2)
  - untitled bound volume, 1964-1975 (Box 3)
  - untitled bound volume, 1928-1950 (Box 2)
  - untitled bound volume, 1950-1956 (Box 2)
  - untitled bound volume, 1956-1961 (Box 2)
  - untitled bound volume, 1961-1964 (Box 2)
  - untitled bound volume, 1964-1967 (Box 2)
  - untitled bound volume, 1967-1970 (Box 2)
  - untitled bound volume, 1970-1973 (Box 2)
  - "State", 1973-1977 (Box 2)
  - "State", 1977-1981 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - untitled loose leaf volume, 1981-1984 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Requisitions, 1924-1934 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence about Classifications, Requisitions, 1929-1958 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Library Statistics, 1932-1961 (Box 4, Folder 19)